NICHOLAS PIASKOSKI

WEB DEVELOPER

Summary

After many years of honing my eye for details and bolstering my problem solving skills in a retail operations environment, I am excited to put these skills to work in web development so that I might get the opportunity to start working on some of life's bigger problems.

Experience

General Assembly

Boston, MA Web Developer Trainee Jun 2017 to Current

Build full stack projects both on my own and as part of small teams.

Chief accomplishments:

- * Built a single player game, using an SPA that interacts with Javascript through JQuery, and that connects with an API through AJAX to handle user authentication and log game moves.
- * Built a web app that interacts with an API that I created. Used Ruby, Rails and Handlebars to build and interact with the API.

Verizon Wireless

Retail Operations specialist

Waynesville, NC Aug 2004 to May 2017

Major Accomplishments:

- * Used excel to create a bar code generator that would be readable by our inventory scanners to account for a new program where we were buying back old customer equipment that did not have SKUs. Saved the company \$15M over the course of a year through greater inventory accuracy and decreasing the processing time for that inventory at 1700 retail locations.
- * Created a fix to refactor an outdated feature in the Point Of Sale system, which was causing stores to send back no value items to the national warehouse. Saved the company \$17M over the period of three years by eliminating shipping costs and processing times at 1700 retail locations and the national warehouse.
- * Earned a Leading performance rating 6 out of 7 years in my role as Operations Specialist. This the highest performance rating and only 3-5% of employees earn this rating.

Aquarium Specialists

Owner

Jun 1999 to Apr 2003

Dallas, TX

Operation of all aspects of an aquarium maintenance service that provided consulting, design, installation, service, and sales. Attracted new clients via cold calls and networking within the aquarium professional and hobby communities. Prepared and presented proposals to existing and prospective clients. Coordinated with construction contractors on custom installations. Generated additional sales by educating clients on biological cycles, natural histories of marine creatures and filter technology.

Volunteering

WWOOF USA · Host Madison Co., NC

Mar 2007 to Current

This is a volunteer position where I work as mentor and host to aspiring organic farmers through the organization World Wide Opportunities on Organic Farms. Interns live and work on my homestead farm for anywhere from two weeks to six months, learning about organic growing and living more sustainably.

Contact

■ sunshine.farm.nc@gmail.com

https://3point14guy.github.io/portfolio

\$28-380-3550

◊ Asheville, NC

in nicholas-piaskoski

3point14guy/

Skills

PROGRAMMING

HTMI 5

CSS3

Bootstrap

Javascript

Ruby

Rails

JQuery

AJAX **JSON**

Handlebars

Node.js

Ember.js

Express.js

SQL

postgreSQL

MongoDB

Mongoose

Git/Github

INVENTORY MANAGEMENT

SAP

Education

Auburn University

Master's level course work and research in aquaculture completed

University Of Massachussetts Bachelor's of Science Biology

Awards

Verizon Wireless · Powerful Answers 2015 Award for identifying improvements for reverse logistics.

Verizon Wireless · Winner's Circle 2005 & 2006 Award for exceeding 110% of sales quota